Krish NAik: Just wait on it to change a little bit, huh?
Krish NAik: Right now.
Krish NAik: Okay, Jessica. Guys, give me,
Krish NAik: In the meantime, everybody switch on your, Lightning AI accounts, that's it? Because, we'll be, back with the same thing today, Slut Gwen part.
Krish NAik: Last week, anybody tried?
Krish NAik: the model part.
Krish NAik: By changing the model and others.
Krish NAik: So please, switch on your Lightning icons.
Krish NAik: All right, Murtha, that right? Yeah, yeah, just quickly.
Krish NAik: Let me just switch your camera.
Krish NAik: Alright, okay, chatting, the fourth optional video needs to be removed, as there was already free.
Krish NAik: I will inform the abstain on that one.
Krish NAik: Alright, so everybody please, switch on to your Lightning AI accounts.
Krish NAik: Okay?
Krish NAik: The pen part only, we'll be doing. Today, even I have my graduate exams.
Krish NAik: So tomorrow, I think, you, also meals from the Academy ofitesh, like, what meals you got? Because I told, the ops team, today there will be class, tomorrow there will be the class. That's all. Tomorrow in the morning, I have an exam, that's it.
Krish NAik: Do you teach or take a class? No, no, no, no, I have my graduated class.
Krish NAik: The riding, I'm sorry.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I think, let's start.
Krish NAik: I think there were no issues today with respect to joining the meeting link.
Krish NAik: Okay, no messages still. So let me start sharing.
Krish NAik: Just wait, I will look into the chat.
Krish NAik: This is desktop 2.
Krish NAik: Did you say tomorrow? Yeah, tomorrow there will be any cars.
Krish NAik: Okay, what is the mail sent? Hope this message, to conduct,
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, I think the ops team made a mistake, because the,
Krish NAik: At night, also, I have a session that was canceled, so Saturday and Sunday for the UDA special.
Krish NAik: For the ragbatch Studio, I'll be doing it.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, everybody please, switch on to your Lightning account.
Krish NAik: Okay, and let's start.
Krish NAik: And, you guys can take a, poll from the, Get,
Krish NAik: Pull Origin Quinn, the Quinn branch.
Krish NAik: So… I think I don't need this anymore. I think this will be fine.
Krish NAik: Alright, so, let me switch on.
Krish NAik: The machine.
Krish NAik: Yeah, yeah, I'm well, just, 2 months. Tomorrow, yes, there won't be any class biology, okay? That's why I told you in the forum also, I think you posted.
Krish NAik: Alright, so let's set up the machine, okay? And everybody, please take the new, pull from the branch, because the branch is exactly the same one. There, I have done some changes.
Krish NAik: Vanilla, last class? Last class, I think, because now I have… I'm not going anywhere, so I think, next week, the deployment part and code discussion will complete. After that, we will start with Langraph, and then finally, we will start with your agentic,
Krish NAik: rag.
Krish NAik: That part, project.
Krish NAik: So I think 2-3 classes will be there from Langraph Foundations, and then directly. Because that project is also a complex one. I want to spend more time on projects in that way.
Krish NAik: the actual practical thing, you guys will be much more clear. Okay, and I think if you guys want, on Thursday night, I can plan a session, okay? Like, because small, small topics are there, I think,
Krish NAik: the page index, metadata enrichment, those are just 60-60 minutes topics, okay? You guys can let me know, so…
Krish NAik: on Thursdays, I can plan for a 60-minute session, or a 90-minute, something like that.
Krish NAik: Okay, because those… that is not part of the syllabus, that's why.
Krish NAik: Okay, does the resource will remain for, some health condition missed much? Does the resource will remain, which resource will remain?
Krish NAik: No, no, not till Thursday morning, Thursday night.
Krish NAik: from 9.30, so, like, 9.30 to 11, or 9.30 to 10.30. Just 60 minutes, because those topics are really, really small. It's not, like, very big topics that…
Krish NAik: And if something is out of the syllables, that's why I will keep it in the extra class.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me just, get a, GPU. Okay, and I'll be select, selecting L4TS, just like last time, in the last class also, we are working with L4TS, so let me request, I think, 2 minutes request time is there.
Krish NAik: Raul is telling, Lightning AI credit, get one very quickly if you are using GPS. See, if you are using GPU, I think,
Krish NAik: It depends upon the GPU, which GPU, actually, you are working with, like, L4TS?
Krish NAik: Just look into the providers.
Krish NAik: Because I think the cheapest provider is… one is VoltageRank and Nabius. But I feel that a lot of lag is there in their machines. Whereas AWS GCP instances are much better, faster.
Krish NAik: That is my personal experience.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think 33 grades are free using GPUs, Raul, you have to understand, okay?
Krish NAik: A lot of limitations are there. Collab provides you, but collab doesn't give you any access with respect to Docker, Demon, or anything.
Krish NAik: That is the main problem with collab.
Krish NAik: And even the RAM is also low for high-intensity tasks, like the task that we are doing. Because right now, in a single GPU, we'll be running so many things. First of all, the OCR model.
Krish NAik: Second of all, the PP detection layout model. Third is your embedding model. Fourth is your
Krish NAik: Re-rank our model. Fifth is your LLL. So, 5 things you are running on a single GP.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: So, I think my machine is ready. Let me make a switch.
Krish NAik: Okay, okay, not an issue.
Krish NAik: Alright, I think I can start with my item. Okay, so everybody? Just…
Krish NAik: Connect it with your SSH, so Ctrl-D.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think I have… I can increase the font a little.
Krish NAik: Hmm, kind of via SSH… I think it will work.
Krish NAik: Which GPU to select? L40S. L40S. L40S.
Krish NAik: I think the font is visible for everyone.
Krish NAik: Yes, or should I encrypt the form? Please let me know.
Krish NAik: Because the screen resolution is 2K, because of that, the font might be smaller.
Krish NAik: It's okay, alright. So, just be in the branch, and everybody, the last machine that you have been using, just do a git, pull.
Krish NAik: Origin, and then Quinn, the name of the branch.
Krish NAik: I have increased the amount of income.
Krish NAik: Venkat, I think.
Krish NAik: Okay, so once you guys are ready with the machine, please let me know.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think…
Krish NAik: I think only Murthas are tested, with the,
Krish NAik: Murthaza, you told me in the chat which model you tested, 4-bit or 8-bit?
Krish NAik: Int 8, okay, the 4 billion one. Alright, fine.
Krish NAik: going through VL Instructive V810. I'm using a different model, I've done the major testing with, Cyanking in the last class, which initially I picked up.
Krish NAik: That, that is the one. So let me just, first of all, show you the Docker Compose file.
Krish NAik: in the Docker Compose, so that's why I've opened this file directly.
Krish NAik: So you will see that this was the model, 23VL, 4 billion instruct, AQ. Okay, so a quantized model, so this is the model that I have tested.
Krish NAik: And other than that, in your .vnv.
Krish NAik: I think the .env file is not in your, profiles, so just have a quick check. So, I will just copy-paste this entire thing in Notion, okay? So that you guys can directly copy-paste and update the .env, because in your .env file.
Krish NAik: during the Docker Compose, the model name will be picked up, okay? So, let me just paste it in motion.
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, pull again. Always look into, the, I can say… the commits in GitHub.
Krish NAik: So, I think this is Ultimate Rap Ports, okay? So, we'll be here.
Krish NAik: Okay, so last class already I've given this, so I will just update the same thing here.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, everybody just be sure you are copy-pasting the same thing.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in Notion, I have added it, you guys can get it from the Notion.
Krish NAik: Please create a new one.
Krish NAik: Instead of override.
Krish NAik: Alright, you want me to… because in the last class, things were different, that's why. And I have updated the model, so I think the old .ebnb is not required in this case. Okay.
Krish NAik: Because majorly, it's the same thing.
Krish NAik: The only change, will be, in the model.
Krish NAik: Hmm, I don't… okay.
Krish NAik: It looks like this is the older one only.
Krish NAik: Just wait, let me just delete it.
Krish NAik: Okay, yes, the sign gaming one is correct.
Krish NAik: I missed it, please ping, Ravi stealing the, I missed it, please ping the page link in… Motion link is same for the past 5 months, Ravi. There has been no change in the motion link. It's pretty much the same one.
Krish NAik: Once you guys have updated, please let me know.
Krish NAik: in the chat that, yes, your SSH configuration is also ready.
Krish NAik: So that,
Krish NAik: we can start with the Docker Compose part. So, first of all, let me tell you what is the change, okay? So, right now, I've been working with a single profile, very specifically.
Krish NAik: And, if you look into, so… let me just increase the font here, okay? And let me collapse this window, which is not required.
Krish NAik: So, right here.
Krish NAik: So this is the Hugging Face mounting directory for the model that I'll be using, and this is the LLM that I have used.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is a quantized version, 4-bit. I know that it will run inside that. And this time, the GPU memory utilization, I've decreased it. You can keep it, like, 0.35. I've tested with 03167. If I'm making it lesser than 0.3, oh no error I am getting. Okay, so I felt that this is enough, at least, for a 4-bit model to be executing on it.
Krish NAik: GPU.
Krish NAik: And the rest of the things are pretty much the same, there hasn't any changes here, okay? So, majorly, this is the thing.
Krish NAik: Till what time Notion and out of the course. Notion is my personal Notion project, so it will be there always. I know.
Krish NAik: Okay, even after 2 years, 3 years, I am. Because Notion, I never delete anything.
Krish NAik: Other things I cannot say, like, based on your course validity and those things matter, but the notion will be there.
Krish NAik: Okay, so only with respect to the model update, so this is the model in the VLLM.
Krish NAik: That we'll be working with. Okay, so based on this.
Krish NAik: The same thing, I have kept it where in Notion also. If you check the,
Krish NAik: model name, the same model name that I have passed it in. That's the only thing for now.
Krish NAik: And actually, I felt that, because when I was working with OpenAI, yes, I can say, because when you are actually working with 4-bit models.
Krish NAik: Somehow?
Krish NAik: As compared to your original LLM, for example, like, working with GPT-4,
Krish NAik: the quantized model will be somehow toward the lower side, always understand the performance, okay? The degradation in the performance will be very less, probably 3-4%,
Krish NAik: But, again, like, you cannot compare it directly. So, the quality of the responses you will be getting, little bit lower.
Krish NAik: Okay. Because I felt that if I will be using the raw model, and if you look into, this is a 4 billion one, I'm not using the 8 billion one also, because the 8 billion one is taking more RAM, so running it in L40S,
Krish NAik: I filed at, the room.
Krish NAik: I always leave at least 4 to 5 GB of VRAM, so that an extra room, that if any process pops up, okay, that others are not being blocked, at least. So, for that case of 4 billion model, I felt that it's good within 4-bit operation.
Krish NAik: Pratamesh, 10 classes, man. If you miss… Nothing I can do.
Krish NAik: I'll be sharing the Google form, don't worry, give me a reminder later on. Everybody, once you guys are ready, please let me know. Then, quickly we will start.
Krish NAik: With the first hunt.
Krish NAik: And I have kept a Docker Compose testing file also, I have added it so that it becomes easier for you.
Krish NAik: Okay, so everybody ready?
Krish NAik: Sanketh, ready, Balaji, ready, what about others? Please say ready, ready, ready. Because if I start executing the region, might say that we might miss something. Ready? All right, fine. So, simply open the file, if you are in your local.
Krish NAik: Okay, so if, our Docker Compose testing file, I have kept it.
Krish NAik: So, majorly, I will start with the first profile that I have, because the second profile, daily, I have not, changed, because the original model was not getting loaded, it was taking a lot of RAM. So, moved with the first profile mainly right now.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, let's build the entire one. So, you can directly take the same command just like last time. In the quint testing file, also, you had compose profiles.
Krish NAik: local LLM docker, you can, open this file.
Krish NAik: as a Markdown extension also, but I know that this is a bash command that I'll be executing so directly. So it's pretty much the same one. Now, I'll be bringing up all the services in one shot, okay, because this is the local LLM profile that I am using.
Krish NAik: Alright, so…
Krish NAik: the same thing I'm just showing you here. Okay, if you have taken a clone, once you have set the .env file, then comes build and start everything. So, here you have the docker compose command.
Krish NAik: Okay, and just like last class, the command is exactly the same, but I have kept it separately.
Krish NAik: Alright, so now what I will do, so let's switch back to our terminal.
Krish NAik: Okay, and let's start the process.
Krish NAik: Okay. It will take some time.
Krish NAik: Because all the images will be pulled, the services will be starting, so that's why this process will take some time.
Krish NAik: I think in the meantime, Pratmish was asking for the Google form. I can share it with you.
Krish NAik: Alright, I have shared the Google form.
Krish NAik: Actually, I don't need this page anymore, so I will just shift it here.
Krish NAik: I'll just…
Krish NAik: Rahul is asking, Lightning AI kept track if you open multiple accounts. Yes, with the same IP, if you try to…
Krish NAik: Sign up into multiple accounts. Then, simply, like, it won't give you the credits.
Krish NAik: There are a listing, so do we need to buy credit?
Krish NAik: One option that you can have, like, if you're working with cloud, okay, you can get an instance from your cloud account also. Purchasing the credit is not really necessary.
Krish NAik: You can use any. The core idea is that you should have a GPU provider, and inside that GPU instance, you, can
Krish NAik: basically run all the tasks, because once you have the instance, the rest of the process is exactly the same. You have to do git clone, switch the branch, run the command. Done.
Krish NAik: So, purchasing regularly is not necessary. If you have any cloud accounts, launch an instance and do an SSH into that. That also works.
Krish NAik: Melinda is asking, are we doing step 3.4? Okay, exactly, I don't know the number, but I… we are doing step 2. If you look into the new docker-compost testing.md file that I've kept it in the branch, this is the first step.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: L40, yes, yes, yes, L40, yes.
Krish NAik: You can use, one, like, A100, right?
Krish NAik: With a 40GB variant also. That also works, but L40S will be cheaper.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let's wait for the VLLM to be start up. Satish, not able to… The command is GET
Krish NAik: Pull, origin. You have to be inside the branch. Don't be inside the master branch. First of all, do a git switch.
Krish NAik: Gwen?
Krish NAik: Okay, comment to that, and then put Satish.
Krish NAik: VLLM will take some time. If I show you the logs of VLLM… so, just wait, let me look into the logs once.
Krish NAik: Alright, so the VLLM logs will be for sure towards the higher side.
Krish NAik: Alright, so yes, the startup will take time. Always take, like, 5 to 10 minutes time, because the entire infra is getting started, and VLLM backend is actually quite a memory-intensive task, so it is taking time.
Krish NAik: Alright, so finally we got 200, so I feel that, this is fine. VLLM is up.
Krish NAik: Alright, so let me just close this one.
Krish NAik: The next logs that I can look into is the application logs.
Krish NAik: Okay. And, for your reference, like, I have kept all the commands for log checking also, if you guys directly, like,
Krish NAik: Let me just show you that part also. Okay, otherwise you will say that crawl from where you got the commands. These are simple Docker Compose commands.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in the Docker Compose file, go to the section sets. Here you have all the commands, because you just need to change the container, like app, VLLM, Ulama, quadrant, and that will.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, please have a check on that now.
Krish NAik: So, first of all, I looked into that, now I will look into the app part. So, in the section 6, you will get the commands, that's why I picked it.
Krish NAik: Alright, now let me look into the application logs.
Krish NAik: Alright, from here also, I can see there is no, like, any type of issue.
Krish NAik: Okay, so pretty much the… must…
Krish NAik: Perfect one, I can say. I have no issues here. Now, in the next step, let me just close this, logs. I don't want to log into that.
Krish NAik: Now, the next thing that you can verify is your, ULAMA part.
Krish NAik: Okay, so Section 2 is pretty much done, and in one shot, if you, want to look into, you can look into the process also. Like, all the containers are running or not, because already you got it in the logs, but if you want to look into the… yes.
Krish NAik: Well, this is…
Krish NAik: And right now, I can see the application, Ulama, Quadrant, okay, and even the visualizer is up, button, VLLN. So, majorly, all the services are. So, everybody, please do the verification, and then let me know.
Krish NAik: Everybody, please do the verification, because step-by-step, I'm telling you, that's why. First, VLLM is up, done. Application is up, done. Okay.
Krish NAik: So, from here, you can do that.
Krish NAik: Strange, Shiva is feeling strange, I just joined to check if the class was even got an, even will…
Krish NAik: No, actually, Shiva, I think there is, some issue, but the ops team has made a mistake. Okay, that's why I told it in the forum today, we have a class.
Krish NAik: Anything else discussed today after the project? No, no, no. Nothing else.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, let's get back and, look into…
Krish NAik: The ulama part, because your ulama should also be up… okay.
Krish NAik: Alright, so let me look into the OLAMA list.
Krish NAik: I think where is my sh… Product.
Krish NAik: Okay, so right now you can see that I don't have the OCR model, so in that case, what we have to do? We have to pull the model. So, let's get the model.
Krish NAik: I think, to download the model,
Krish NAik: O lama, pull GLM OCR letters, okay? So, the command, I should have added it here only, but, fine. Let me just download the model nodes.
Krish NAik: Ul… Glm OCR latest.
Krish NAik: Abhishek, which one? Dopper Compose Testing?
Krish NAik: I think everybody can pull the model, because exactly the command is not there. If you are, if you don't know which command in the last
Krish NAik: class also, that command was shared in the quint testing file. Because the quint testing markdown, we were using it in the last class, today's class, we are working with the Docker Compose. If you don't know that command, simply, like,
Krish NAik: Let me just show you. Well, the same thing, the references are always there, just you have to be,
Krish NAik: Smart to pick it up, okay? So, if you look into, this is the command to pull it.
Krish NAik: Okay, now I can do an ulama list, you will see that the GLM OCR model will be available.
Krish NAik: Okay? So in your case, also, I think the model won't be there.
Krish NAik: G, L, M, Olama List.
Krish NAik: Alright, so right now, I have the…
Krish NAik: I can say the OCR model.
Krish NAik: Everybody?
Krish NAik: Till this point, have you done it? Please let me know.
Krish NAik: Step by step.
Krish NAik: Please let me know in the chat.
Krish NAik: Alright, right now…
Krish NAik: I want to get one thing.
Krish NAik: Okay, are we executing Docker Compose first?
Krish NAik: No, no, no, like, see, both the files are pretty much same Rahul. When testing, the commands are same, but exactly the same commands are there, and the same commands are here.
Krish NAik: So, when last class I used, this class I just created a new file, Docker Compose.
Krish NAik: Alright, let me just, look into… The process once.
Krish NAik: If anybody is stuck, please let me know. Till this point that I have done.
Krish NAik: Anybody is stuck?
Krish NAik: Anywhere?
Krish NAik: Yes or no, at least say something in the chat.
Krish NAik: Go here, pull command is not there in the markdown fella, we shake, last class already that command we have used so many times.
Krish NAik: That's why, it's in the quint testing file, that's why I showed you. If you…
Krish NAik: See, in quint testing, if you go into that, this is the same command, and you have to be a little bit towards that blindly copy-pasting, you have to understand that, okay, last time I did an ULAMA list, this time what I have to do? Change the command list to pull, and the name of the OCR model.
Krish NAik: Okay. Otherwise, get it, because in the last lesson, I have already shown, so the idea is that you guys can do it. Milind is telling I'm just…
Krish NAik: Working compute switch methods are relearning again, alright?
Krish NAik: This part is pretty much…
Krish NAik: Everybody, please take 2 minutes and just be sure you have downloaded the module.
Krish NAik: just begin track, meaning what you are telling, okay, switching machines and other things. I know, like, when you work with an SSH machine, but again, I think 2 minutes will be enough for everyone to be on the same track.
Krish NAik: You are telling hyphen A. I don't want to look into the hidden processes right now.
Krish NAik: Here, PS IFNA, within the… this environment, it won't work.
Krish NAik: It's docker PS hyphen A, I don't want to do right now.
Krish NAik: I was actually looking into whether, Olama is using, GPU or CPU, because of that, that particular process.
Krish NAik: Oh, right, I can see that,
Krish NAik: Okay, the Ulama is using GPU only, because if I use the CPU,
Krish NAik: Okay, the response time is very, very high. Again, if you remember last time I executed in the machine, okay?
Krish NAik: Yes, NVIDIA SMI will also help you, if you want to understand, like, how much… NVIDIA-SMI.
Krish NAik: So pretty much you can see ULAMA that is getting used here, okay, as well as the BLM. So initially, like, it takes some time, so sometimes you, might need to restart the container if you don't see the process.
Krish NAik: Okay, again, I'm repeating. If you don't see the process, please restart the container, because first, when the container started, there was no OCR model.
Krish NAik: Because of that, by default, it will switch to the CPU. Once you have downloaded the model, if request, please restart the container.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let's go step by step till this point, once you guys have given me the verification.
Krish NAik: Because by default, in the script, it is mentioned that if no models are there, let's start with SCP.
Krish NAik: If you have the model, restart the container, automatically the switch to G2 will take.
Krish NAik: Okay, so,
Krish NAik: Alright, I am sharing. What is the… I, haven't seen any process, still looking,
Krish NAik: Took Lightning AI time, can walk through the step one more time. Running NVID SMI shows the VLM process. Okay, so do one thing.
Krish NAik: There are two options, actually, whenever you are, doing this. The first one is, like, restart the container, okay?
Krish NAik: Just wait, I am spacing the command in motion.
Krish NAik: Because I think, restart command is there or not.
Krish NAik: No, simply… You can do the restart of the container, but the command is there or not,
Krish NAik: Pulled out… okay, this is the coin testing file…
Krish NAik: You have to just write restart ulama, but again, I don't think I have kept the command here.
Krish NAik: Just tweet.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, let me just, write the command for that, because in the docker-compose testing file is also not there, I think, and just wait.
Krish NAik: You have to write, docker space compose hyphen F, then, docker hyphen compose, the name of the file, basically, that gpu.yml.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, here you can see, like, till this point, the command will be exactly the same. After that, you have to just write restart space ulama.
Krish NAik: If it is not there,
Krish NAik: Let me add it in Notion, okay?
Krish NAik: That's why I've kept it a lot of, sean's also a bit.
Krish NAik: This is force recreate. Now, this is also you can do, but again,
Krish NAik: See, this is, force recreate Olama. This option also you can use. Multiple ways are there. So, first of all, let me just, paste the commandments. I have the command.
Krish NAik: Okay, quote, if you wouldn't mind.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is a command.
Krish NAik: That's pretty much the same command, just restart, olama, done.
Krish NAik: Okay, everybody, please do have a check.
Krish NAik: Once you have restarted the container.
Krish NAik: It will take some time to switch to the GPU, but you can see the process.
Krish NAik: Everybody please provide the verification?
Krish NAik: Restart the container.
Krish NAik: Okay, and the command that I have used… okay, do the verification.
Krish NAik: Using the command, I think that command is already there.
Krish NAik: Ulama PS also you can do it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is the command that you need to run after that. So, please tell me, everybody, is it running on the GPU?
Krish NAik: Then, if it doesn't work, please tell.
Krish NAik: But I think it should work for everyone.
Krish NAik: Methesh is telling not able to see, even I did the restart.
Krish NAik: You won't see, once you execute the process, then look back into your, main command, which is this one, docker compose hyphen F.
Krish NAik: You will see, the status will be, new. That number of minutes will be less, and that we do the verification.
Krish NAik: I was trying Nebius for reinitializing… Nebius machines, I felt that, Murta, it's a little bit laggy as compared to AWS and GCP. That is my personal experience, but again, I cannot say that every instance is laggy, that you get it from NEBS, because Nebius is cheaper, so…
Krish NAik: If it is working fine, great. But, just have a look.
Krish NAik: Sometimes I feel that I type it, it is reflected in the terminal after 3 seconds or 4 seconds, so a little bit lag, I guess.
Krish NAik: So guys, please let me know if the process is working or not.
Krish NAik: If it's not working, then manually we will do it. That's why I'm asking.
Krish NAik: Then the manual process, we have to do it.
Krish NAik: I have to write the Docker error.
Krish NAik: Alright, let's start with the manual process. I will just copy the same thing. I will also stop my process, so that, everyone is on the same track, okay? Alright, see? Now, what I will do?
Krish NAik: docker compose hyphen app, docker compose gpu.yml, restartOLAM.
Krish NAik: Okay? The container restart is done.
Krish NAik: Now, I think the process should be moved from here. Let me check with NVIDIA IFN SMI. You will see the process is gone after the restart.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: See, guys, restart, the process is gone. Now,
Krish NAik: Let me just, I don't want the restart part.
Krish NAik: Okay, first of all, the model is available or not?
Krish NAik: Let me show you that.
Krish NAik: Let me do an Ulama list.
Krish NAik: The model is setting right now.
Krish NAik: I don't have, any issues.
Krish NAik: Now, in the next step, let me…
Krish NAik: run it, because the direct option is to run it, so let me just take that one, just wait.
Krish NAik: Whenever I write Y, I get this one.
Krish NAik: Noted.
Krish NAik: I've just executed the command, so manually I will just paste it here.
Krish NAik: That's soul.
Krish NAik: You can get the docker execution command.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is basically an eco command, just to check, okay, because the process is running, now I have to do the verification once. Okay, so once I have executed the command, you will see, in the process, the GPU can. So please do the verification once.
Krish NAik: I have pasted both the commands in Notion, you can copy, paste in the Notion, okay?
Krish NAik: Everybody please provide a confirmation?
Krish NAik: have run above command getting response, should I wait? You should get the response immediately, because it's running on the GPU. If it is running on the CPU, then the response will take time.
Krish NAik: Because this is a smoke test that I have done, basically, right now. Just to check that I'm getting a response from the…
Krish NAik: I'm getting restarting message, and the response is taking time.
Krish NAik: Okay, just in the other terminal, do an NVIDIA SMI, because I feel that, it should be working.
Krish NAik: the other command, if I show you the ulama process also, Okay, the Ulama, PS.
Krish NAik: I can see the process, because the same command I have added it here. Okay, check the process. Ulama process.
Krish NAik: Nothing.
Krish NAik: Now, this is the command to check the process.
Krish NAik: And very specifically, in the container, if you feel that… very specifically, I can do an NVIDIA SMI inside the container also, that whether it has access to GPU or not.
Krish NAik: Okay, cool.
Krish NAik: Now, this is within the container I am doing the NVIDIA SMI, not, outside.
Krish NAik: Okay, so we have a step-by-step. Now the NVIDIA shows Ullama process Balaji? Great.
Krish NAik: I've kept all the commands to debug.
Krish NAik: If…
Krish NAik: Okay, so everybody please provide the confirmation.
Krish NAik: That tells this point for everybody good so far. Everybody… Olama is running on, GPU.
Krish NAik: Yes?
Krish NAik: Please let me know. If it doesn't run on the GPU, then what will happen? In the configuration file, I have kept it 120 seconds as…
Krish NAik: your timeout. Okay, so if it runs on the CPU, by default, I know that the response cannot be within 120 seconds. Because of that, you will get a timeouter.
Krish NAik: That's why it's important. Otherwise, what is the purpose of using a GPU machine, if I am not using the GPU?
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, that is the application locks, Satish. Okay, I'm not worried about the application locks. Application locks are fine. Alright, so the ulama process is ready. Now, what I will do, let's, get back here. I think, where is my process?
Krish NAik: So, I think this is where the stack is ready, and in the last class already, you guys were, working with
Krish NAik: Quadrant. So, let's open quadrant.
Krish NAik: Okay, let's open the collection.
Krish NAik: Right now, there are no collections, so the collection will be created when I'll be hitting the API,
Krish NAik: Okay, so the application lock, already I have shown you before, so I'm not going to show you again. Alright, let me open the FastAPI application.
Krish NAik: Everybody, please let me know.
Krish NAik: that… Quadrant UI is opening. The Fast API application is opening. Yes.
Krish NAik: Because, when I do the ingestion, now,
Krish NAik: Your embedding model will also be re-initialized.
Krish NAik: Okay, so please let me know. I have not started with a, hot start arriving.
Krish NAik: So everybody, are we in the same track?
Krish NAik: Quadrant opening.
Krish NAik: Fastapi application opening.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, 3 people only said yes, what about others?
Krish NAik: Anywhere you got stuck, simply say, I am stuck.
Krish NAik: Ashok, yes, alright. Rajat is telling,
Krish NAik: Rajat, check the spelling. You are writing P-lama, not Olama.
Krish NAik: Whenever you are copy-pasting, please do have a check.
Krish NAik: Alright, let's start with the ingestion, and let's see that whether we are getting any errors or not, okay? So, I think, choose file… the same, DocLink technical report, the file that we have been using for the past 2 to 3 weeks.
Krish NAik: Let's start with the, 5. Send an empty value, okay, because these things you guys have already done, 512 chunks, this is fine, true. Let's execute.
Krish NAik: Okay? Okay, before executing, it's important to look into the application logs, okay? So, let's get the, section set. Let me start with the application logs first of all.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is from where I'll be getting the application logs.
Krish NAik: Now, once I hit execute, I will switch back to the terminal.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you can see post slash ingest slash file, initializing them better.
Krish NAik: embedding provider, Gwen.
Krish NAik: Alright, so the embedding model is getting downloaded in the first request.
Krish NAik: Okay, so the model weights are right now in the local machine, I can see.
Krish NAik: Parsing initialized, total 9 pages that I have.
Krish NAik: Because rest of the logs are pretty much same.
Krish NAik: Now we will see that, okay, once the… now what will happen?
Krish NAik: the… it will hit the OCR model.
Krish NAik: Okay, and from there, I'll be getting the response. Now, that response that I have from there, our structure of our chunking that will take place.
Krish NAik: So…
Krish NAik: the OCR model response, and the embedding. So, it will take a little bit of time, not a lot.
Krish NAik: Now, if there is any issue with the Olama connection, now here I'll be getting some type of error, like HTTP connection pool or timeout, something like that.
Krish NAik: Alright, I'm, looking into parsing. Okay, escaping LLM extraction for, chunk docklink, keeping modality table, image cropped is equal to true. Okay, fine, this is where, and finally, I can see total 36 chunks that have been created, creating collection documents.
Krish NAik: the upstart operation to VectorDB has been done. So let's open it here and reload this page.
Krish NAik: Okay, so right now, I can see, okay, and even if you look into… okay, and here, based on that, you will be getting the information also.
Krish NAik: Alright, so my docling.pdf…
Krish NAik: Alright, so now, let's…
Krish NAik: get into our application. The first phase is done. Okay, now, based on the tables, I think, last week also, I have, kept, I think, few questions were there. You can take it from Notion, because now I'll be trying to ask a question from the tables.
Krish NAik: I will go to the generate section, and let's see that whether it works or not.
Krish NAik: Let's reduce the number of numbers to 15…
Krish NAik: Top 10 is equal to 5. I think for everybody, the upset operation work, yes or no, please tell me. It will take some time, but it should not take a lot of time also.
Krish NAik: Rajat is telling 23 VL, 8 billion instruct. I'm not using that model only, Rajat.
Krish NAik: everybody see the model that you are using. So, I think,
Krish NAik: Just wait, everybody. The model name should be this one.
Krish NAik: No… It's adjustment.
Krish NAik: In your .env, I've kept it, the name of the model. It has to be this one.
Krish NAik: No.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is .vnb…
Krish NAik: Okay, no, no, no, this is local one, when I got confused. Just wait, let me open the lightning here.
Krish NAik: I'm very flakini.
Krish NAik: Because if you pass a different model name, it won't work, and then you have to, simply restart your VLLM container. Okay, recreate it, restart it, two options are there. So, in our case, what is the name?
Krish NAik: Please do have a check on this one. This is the name of the model.
Krish NAik: Because that's what I have mentioned in .env.
Krish NAik: How many have updated the code base? You have done a git pull origin.
Krish NAik: Yes, please let me know.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, if you want to check, very specifically for your
Krish NAik: One, okay, so I think, alright.
Krish NAik: Let's do a call, okay, and see what are the models which are available. You can do a simple call also, that's why I've kept this particular command.
Krish NAik: You will see the model here when you run this. This is the VLLM model that you have. In your case, which model you guys are using? Try to debug. I am pasting the command. It's already there also. Do a curl to the VLLM server. Right now, I'm doing a curl to the VLLM server, and from there, I'm getting the response in J form.
Krish NAik: Okay, so Abhis Sheikh.
Krish NAik: And, others, please, have a check on that one.
Krish NAik: Because the quadrant container is 1.13, I think I have updated the quadrant container to 1.17.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright. Methesh is telling this is correct, but still getting the issue, all right.
Krish NAik: Alright, you are getting the issue in your case. I got model not available error. Model is not available, Abhishek, so please check to the command. Mitesh, in your case, just copy-paste that as…
Krish NAik: I think in Notion, the model is not updated. Alright, alright, alright, alright. If in Notion it is not updated, it will throw you an error for sure.
Krish NAik: In Notion.
Krish NAik: I think this is only in Notion, no? The sineQV23VL4B, and struct. This is the model that I am using. So I feel that it's correct here.
Krish NAik: Please check.
Krish NAik: This value, this value has to be correct.
Krish NAik: Because every, LLM model has its own model card in Hugging Face. Based on that, we run the model.
Krish NAik: Restart the BLLM?
Krish NAik: Okay, that option you can always do, like, you can recreate the container also.
Krish NAik: But whenever you are doing a kernel, okay, so you should get that model, that exact model that I have.
Krish NAik: Can you restart?
Krish NAik: Please let me know.
Krish NAik: The sign, Rajat. In your case, Rajat, you are getting, the correct response.
Krish NAik: The response is same, just like mine only, no?
Krish NAik: I cannot sleep.
Krish NAik: then what 404, where you are getting 404? In the chat, I cannot see any 404.
Krish NAik: Because when you say 404, please let me know that, from where you are getting the 404.
Krish NAik: The process is simple, like, once you have,
Krish NAik: done it for captioning, we're using the LLM.
Krish NAik: See, Rajat, when you were doing that, OpenAI, not found error, the model quaint 3 billion. Just check, some were,
Krish NAik: You have, used it. Because I can see this is the old model name, that's why.
Krish NAik: Alright, let me… so, because when 3… Vl8 billion instruct.
Krish NAik: First, do the verification that in your .env file, whether you have the correct one or not.
Krish NAik: This is the first step.
Krish NAik: Then I will, move back into the next one.
Krish NAik: Because this is the first step.
Krish NAik: Let me, look in.
Krish NAik: Okay, because in the codebase, I have not hard-coded anywhere, this is the only place, through which
Krish NAik: Okay, now, this is one place, and even look into your docker-compose. The GPU file. In the first profile of the local hyphen LLM, this is the model or not. This is the second check, please do.
Krish NAik: Please do have a check on both of these guys.
Krish NAik: Milind is telling ENV file looks like the issue. Even I feel that, because the GPU, Docker Compose file, this is the exact name of the command. That's why I told you, do the verification.
Krish NAik: Jatinar Bali is telling his branch may be wrong.
Krish NAik: No, I think, all the quant files I have in a single queen branch only, no? That's why I feel that.
Krish NAik: So whoever millions and others, please do have a check on that.
Krish NAik: Okay, because these are the main two places where the name of the model is there.
Krish NAik: Okay, so please let me know.
Krish NAik: No, in the deployment branch, it will not,
Krish NAik: Okay, in the… no, no, in the deployment branch, I have never used any quen model, so I don't think, he is in the deployment branch as well.
Krish NAik: Melinda Seling, should I run Docker Compose again?
Krish NAik: You know, before running, try to look that where that 8 billion instructor's coming, that is the minimum.
Krish NAik: Because one entry is in .env file, the other one is the docker-compose file. Other than that, I don't have any other entries.
Krish NAik: You have to understand, it has to be inside the VLL.
Krish NAik: Because in the code, there is no other entry.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, now let me just try to ask a question here.
Krish NAik: Abhishek is telling, I think the issue is delayed refresh option. Okay, it can be. You might have copied that one, so just have a check. Melind is telling mismatch is in .vnv. Alright, fine. You debug the issue, that is the main thing. You should be able to debug the main issue.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let's start with some questions.
Krish NAik: Because I'm, really going very, very…
Krish NAik: Let's start with something, with a table, and let me see that whether I'm getting any response or not.
Krish NAik: Okay, now the first response will take time. Why?
Krish NAik: Because the re-ranking model will be downloaded from the internet, okay? So, you can look into the logs, you will see that the first, loading 23 re-ranker model, because of that, the first response will take time. And right now, I got in 200, so I feel that I got some type of response here.
Krish NAik: Okay, and I can see with, this is found on table page, also referenced in the table image on page 5, which shows… actually, this retailing in Quinn is, a little bit better with respect to the answers that I feel.
Krish NAik: Okay, because it actually tells you in the answer where everything is. Okay, it'll become much easier.
Krish NAik: OpenAI, we are not using anything with respect to OpenAI. Our entire stack is based on Pen Satish.
Krish NAik: That's why we are working in the quen branch. OpenAI, we are working in the master branch and the deployment branch.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: So, guys, please have a check, because right now, I can see that I asked the question from the table, and I am getting a response. So, everybody.
Krish NAik: Go slowly, I will wait 5 to 10 minutes, I know. Can you show the question parameters?
Krish NAik: Question parameters, like, are you talking about this question?
Krish NAik: Rajat?
Krish NAik: Which parameters are you talking about? This is the question that I have asked.
Krish NAik: I think this question is there in your notion also.
Krish NAik: What is the TTL backend? So here, a few questions are there. You can copy-paste all the questions that I am testing today. I will keep it in a separate code block.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is the first question.
Krish NAik: Meanwhile, right?
Krish NAik: Let me try to ask some different questions this time.
Krish NAik: This time, the response will be much faster, the native backend. I can see that I'm getting the response.
Krish NAik: That's a little…
Krish NAik: Everybody please have a check.
Krish NAik: You will see the response time will be pretty much low after the first request.
Krish NAik: Okay, yes, I am getting pretty much correct person. It worked for me, ENV, was the issue, had the wrong value? Great, Mitesh, you solved it. Update and rebuild the docker, looks good, great. Always look into C, right now, because once my core setup is done, then I can actually go and write a single batch script.
Krish NAik: To set up the… to set up everything.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in a single BAS script, I can do all the checks, but once you do it manually, you have to understand the process, step by step. First, make the LLM
Krish NAik: Life. Using what? Using your VLL. That is one container. One container, your OCR is running.
Krish NAik: That is the Ulama container. In one container, your quadrant is running. In one container, your application is running, your FastAP application.
Krish NAik: In that way.
Krish NAik: So, one by one, because one will be connecting with another. If there is some issue with another one, you will see that some type of errors that will come.
Krish NAik: And always do the verification that Ulama is running.
Krish NAik: the ULAMA or the GLM OCR is running on the GPU, because the timeout is 120 seconds.
Krish NAik: Okay, I've not kept it, like, last time I kept it, 1200 seconds. So, it will wait for CPU, but this time, the code I have modified.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, for anybody, till now, anybody got a response, please let me know.
Krish NAik: Let me, try to ask some questions.
Krish NAik: Alright, I can see the response is coming fine, modality, because this is an,
Krish NAik: question that I have asked from the tables, and I feel the quality of the responses from the 4-bit model is quite good.
Krish NAik: Let me remove the double quotes. It can create some issue.
Krish NAik: table structure, which is shown in diagram, page 3, figure PDF, which illustrates the pipeline. Alright, pretty much detailed one. So, please, not able to hear you. Suhan, I think, I'm audible, please let me know, guys.
Krish NAik: Please repeat one more time how you are starting Quadrant and the application service. Satish, to start the entire stack, the command I have given it in your Docker Compose testing, a single file is there.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is the command.
Krish NAik: Because if you ask me to redo all these steps that I have done it from the past hour, okay?
Krish NAik: Because, yes, that is working for me. If it is working, then next check, the OCR model is available or not. Otherwise, download the model, step by step. Motava is telling everything working. Alright.
Krish NAik: Because I actually need to build up a stack within a 48 GB, and if you, look into the, room size also, okay? So, NVD hyphen SMI,
Krish NAik: Yeah, okay, you can see the Python application is taking. So, can anybody tell me Python application is taking Y8GB of RAM?
Krish NAik: Because of what?
Krish NAik: Alright, Ashok, try with different queries. Mine is also working, Viraj, great.
Krish NAik: So, see, 3 main processes. Re-rank are correct.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, Sanket, why packages? See, GPU, don't think about. Packages, you can say in the other way. Technically, PyTorch is using your kind, but the actual thing is the re-ranker model and the embedding model. We have two models. They are using the GPU. That's why the Python process is using it.
Krish NAik: Okay? Always remember, because right now, I have…
Krish NAik: want to… even the PPE dock layout… layout detection model is also doing that.
Krish NAik: Okay, so total 5 things I am running on a single GPU, and if you look into till now, I have close to how much memory left?
Krish NAik: Based on the process, I can say that, yes, 15GB, and the 4-bit model is actually giving me good response, because for a RAN-based application, you really don't need to use models like Anthropic or OpenAI.
Krish NAik: In long-term run, they are very, very costly.
Krish NAik: Very, very costly. Always remember that. But, if you're actually using a GPU instance, and if you have done a long-term commitment with any cloud provider, whether it's AWS, Ageo, that cost becomes, like, 70% cheaper when you go for a long run, 5-year contract.
Krish NAik: Okay? At least 3 years of contract. In that way, when you go for long-term, this particular solution becomes much, much cheaper if you are actually using everything customized stacked.
Krish NAik: That's why I thought about presenting the entire QuanStack tool, because the quality of the response is good.
Krish NAik: The other stack that we can use is the GINA stack. That stack, also, I love it. GINA has good embedding models, GINA has good re-rankers, but the LLM at that particular point of time, I have to change to something else. Because GINA,
Krish NAik: Actually, LLM part, I feel that, there is a little bit downside. Then, probably, I might switch to a different VL model. So, everybody, please have a check, and then let me know that, yes, everything is working fine on.
Krish NAik: Okay, and if I change my, VLLM model, so… based on that, always I have to update the application, always remember that, because from transformers, I'm using the
Krish NAik: QuenVL processor class, okay, to load up most of the tasks, whether it's my embedding model, read anchor model, that is the main class that we do have.
Krish NAik: So if I change the model, so always have a look into the model card. So during the core discussion, I'll be talking about that. So it's not like that, you can plug and play any model in one shot.
Krish NAik: Always remember what your code supports.
Krish NAik: please, let me know, everyone, because usually I've asked the question from, images and tables.
Krish NAik: And the quality of the response with the details, I feel that it's pretty much correct.
Krish NAik: How many of you are stuck? Simply say that I am stuck. Is there anybody?
Krish NAik: Port support is, in terms of, response format, or request. No, no, no, no. Port support means your backend code to load up the models.
Krish NAik: It means that you'll be using transformers.
Krish NAik: Then you will be defining, like, what is the model definition to loot up the model there, that particular model got sunk in. Okay.
Krish NAik: Satish is telling what is the next step.
Krish NAik: Next step for what? Test out the application.
Krish NAik: Because right now, if it is working, everybody, please do a thorough testing, because I know that this is a 4-bit model. In some way, the performance can be
Krish NAik: a little bit toward the downside, but you will feel the quality of the response is good. You cannot compare it with a enterprise-level LLM, but you will feel that it should be up and working.
Krish NAik: Satish, when you say into the logs, it's telling you waiting, so wait.
Krish NAik: Look into the logs, what is going ahead inside that particular container.
Krish NAik: That is the same thing that I showed you, always look into the logs of a container. Whether it is the VLLM container, whether it is the application container, then only you can debug it.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, debugging becomes problem.
Krish NAik: Mitesh is asking the filter modality. Yes, you can pass the filter modality, no? So I think,
Krish NAik: filter modality, I think it should work.
Krish NAik: If I, let's, get back here.
Krish NAik: Okay, and here, let me add. Filter modality part, you were asking me to add it, fine.
Krish NAik: Just…
Krish NAik: Okay, because in the filter modality, you have the options of, making four things, algorithms, then you have formula, then you have, table, and then you have image, okay, based on that.
Krish NAik: Okay,
Krish NAik: Yes, we will get the response.
Krish NAik: Okay? Methesh, the question that you have asked…
Krish NAik: Four value that can take.
Krish NAik: Algorithm, formula, image, table.
Krish NAik: No, actually, if you don't want to pass anything, I have not kept any condition like null.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why I removed that particular parameter.
Krish NAik: Formula is there.
Krish NAik: Text modalities by default, so, like, okay. So, do the experiment add formula also.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, everybody please let me know, because once we have done the testing, Successfully.
Krish NAik: Or anybody who is stuck anywhere.
Krish NAik: Do we need to do the entire process again, or something like that?
Krish NAik: Balaj is selling stock?
Krish NAik: Okay? How many of you are stuck? Because this process is a little bit… if you are not familiar with Docker, Docker Compose, it becomes a problem.
Krish NAik: That's fine.
Krish NAik: Health status says degraded. Health status, even I have not checked the health status.
Krish NAik: Degraded, let me check the health.
Krish NAik: Because,
Krish NAik: That is fine, okay? Even it's for me, I think. Because I think, this part I have hard-coded it, based on a certain condition, so leave that part.
Krish NAik: Okay? Don't think about degrading. Look into the application logs, always look. Because even for me, I always look into the application log.
Krish NAik: Because that is hard-coded, I can update the variable later on.
Krish NAik: Always look into the process.
Krish NAik: The application logs, majorly, then you can actually debug it.
Krish NAik: Where to check the application logs? You have the command node. For every log checking, I told you in section
Krish NAik: 6, you have the command, basically for which of your container. So, for the application, just follow, then BLLA, molama, quatern, pretty much all the services I have listed it.
Krish NAik: Already showed that also, Satish.
Krish NAik: Alright, so for how many of you successfully, it's pretty much done? Please let me know with yes, yes, yes, yes, in the chat.
Krish NAik: Okay, and a few people, because this was the core one. Next slide, because for our deployment, I won't be using so much a complex stack, really. I will be moving ahead with our normal deployment branch only, with the APIs major.
Krish NAik: Okay, because otherwise, it doesn't make too much sense.
Krish NAik: To do it.
Krish NAik: I'm dead.
Krish NAik: Aniroth is asking, sir, are we also counting the token used? Right now, I'm not added, but using tick token, the package, I can track that. Or using so many, using Comet ML also, you can track it. Using OPIC also, you can do it. Using Landsmith also.
Krish NAik: Melinda's telling consumed all credits is great, but at least it is done, no. Everybody, just remember, if all the credits, just try to…
Krish NAik: Exhausted today only. After that, I think I won't be using Lightning AI. Today will be pretty much the last
Krish NAik: Because this is the extreme use case of GPU.
Krish NAik: Later on, just, you have to understand we can switch to better LLMs.
Krish NAik: And for RAG, I can say that a 4 billion model is more than enough, if the quality of the chunking is good.
Krish NAik: You really don't need to use with those GPT-based models.
Krish NAik: Ashwag, really, I'm not, what is after in Docklink pipeline?
Krish NAik: Based on your query, it totally depends.
Krish NAik: Because I think that, also as a part of the output, I am seeing OCR is disabled. OCR
Krish NAik: OCR is disabled… I'm not sure about OCR is disabled, because if you have the GLM process up and running.
Krish NAik: Then, if the OCR model is not there, Katalisar, then it won't work. That's why.
Krish NAik: Models, Lightning is good, I'm planning to use for quick ES. Actually, for developers, even Moodle is also good. Lightning and Moodle, these two are the main products.
Krish NAik: But the cost is high. In Lightning AI, somehow I feel that $1 is equal to 1 credit. As simple as that. That is the…
Krish NAik: Hmm… Simple math that it works.
Krish NAik: It doesn't matter whether you are getting an academic pricing, any subscription, it's pretty much $1, one credit.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, so please let me know, people with, problems, because I won't be switching off my machine, I will keep it on in the meantime, because if it's…
Krish NAik: it's pretty much done, then I think next week only I'll be doing the deployment and, the code discussion. And for, majorly, the code discussion, I will be doing the discussion for the Quinn branch also, but for the deployment, I won't be using the Quinn branch. Again, I am repeating. For my deployment, I'll be switching back to which branch?
Krish NAik: The deployment branch, the original one that we have been working with.
Krish NAik: And, like, now, if you have this particular, a very similar solution, okay, now this, you can make it completely on-prem, yes or no.
Krish NAik: Now, probably for an on-prem solution, what do you have to do? Can anybody tell me a little bit about on-prem?
Krish NAik: In that case, what do you have to do?
Krish NAik: If you are actually… because you have done the initial testing, what will be… everything local, yes, on-prem means everything local, that's why.
Krish NAik: All self-hosted? No, no, no, no, don't say the meaning of on-prem. If you're doing an on-prem solution, in that case, what will be the first thing? Now, if I'm suggesting it to any financial institutions, okay, the staff, generally, they might say that I don't want to go with the VIN model. Fine, like, a few things I might change.
Krish NAik: Because, the Chinese family, this is completely pure, Chinese family. Probably, I might switch to Elastic Labs products, like Jinna. In most of the cases, they say that we don't want to go ahead with those models. It's fine. Always remember, you can change each and everything.
Krish NAik: Now, the question comes scaling. For scaling, remember, you cannot work only with a 48 GPU. In that case, in the on-frame, whichever GPU that you are getting, be sure it is having, high VRAM.
Krish NAik: like, H200s…
Krish NAik: Okay, at least scaling, because I feel that when you are doing the load testing with at least 10,000 requests, the amount of VRAM spike will be high.
Krish NAik: Okay, and if you're working with vertical scaling, optic containers, in that case, you should always have, like, right now I've taken 48GB, simply multiply 8 by 3. That is always a safer zone to work.
Krish NAik: So, pick up a GPU which is giving you more VRAM for your on-prem-based solutions.
Krish NAik: We just need to set up the GPS, that is the main thing, and for that, always take the decision based on the number of requests. Always look into your MaoDAO. From MaoDAO, you can actually make it.
Krish NAik: I have seen that if you're getting only 1,000 requests, then use a 2x, like 48 into 2, and 96 GB DRAM is more than enough for it.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, now, even my credits will be closed at something.
Krish NAik: So…
Krish NAik: Okay, now, what are the other things that we can add in this process? Can anybody tell me?
Krish NAik: Just think about, because the entire process, you guys know.
Krish NAik: So, what are the other things that we can add into this PIN branch?
Krish NAik: Yes?
Krish NAik: Any suggestions from you guys? Like, what are the things that we can add?
Krish NAik: Please let me know. Raul is asking, what about the P8 models like Clot and so on it? Can we deploy?
Krish NAik: Rahul, you are asking, what about the paid models like Claude, Sonnet, can we deploy those LLMs?
Krish NAik: Google provide you the weights. Those are proprietary products, Rahun, no? Those are… that is not open source.
Krish NAik: In GPT family, you have that GPT OSS, 120 billion model. That is open source, that you can host it. Clouds on it and, those things, you cannot do it, because you don't have the weights only.
Krish NAik: That's right.
Krish NAik: You too.
Krish NAik: Corrective rag, okay, with respect to architectures, those things can be done. Corrective… catch… catch… no, don't say application-level things. Tell me AI things. Don't say application. Say from AI perspective, what are the things that we can do.
Krish NAik: Asian tick rag.
Krish NAik: I'm talking about AI.
Krish NAik: how you can bring more AI into the system. AI.
Krish NAik: Simply, tell me from engineering point of view. Don't say agents or anything.
Krish NAik: If you say agents, with agents, what that you are bringing, yeah, into the system, that part I want to understand.
Krish NAik: Anybody, just think.
Krish NAik: Prompts and model. Okay? You are telling prompts and model. What model you were trying to, bring, Mudassar? You can throw some light on that, like, what model should we bring here? What type of model?
Krish NAik: Satish is telling, I have $4 credit, but still asking to upgrade while running. That is a notification, you can skip that, Satish.
Krish NAik: Generally, when it is below $5, it'll show you that notification, but simply you can skip that.
Krish NAik: Yes, when you say prompts, again, prompts, lead, that is not from AI engineering perspective.
Krish NAik: model.
Krish NAik: Like, what model that anybody, like, what other model that I can bring into the system?
Krish NAik: Sanket is telling, can you include DSPY main? That is fine.
Krish NAik: Again, DSPY, really, I appreciate that you have told, really, like, it is one of the best things.
Krish NAik: But again, very few people do it.
Krish NAik: But again, your approach is correct. Generally, for most of the times, whenever I need prompt automation, in that case, I keep it, because making it as a DSPY program, it is much better. Mitesh, catching is, again, that is application point of view. I'm talking about AI engineering point of view, what you can do.
Krish NAik: Subject utility, like text and image.
Krish NAik: Subject to utility, like text and image, subject to utility?
Krish NAik: Like, text, comma, image.
Krish NAik: Like, what type of utility that you were referring?
Krish NAik: For model…
Krish NAik: Like, exactly, we are working with a VLM. The VLM has already the support for text images.
Krish NAik: like, right now in the field of RAG, what other type of models you can use? Anybody? Anybody has used a hallucination detection model? Now, let me just say, what are the other type of models that you can
Krish NAik: Anybody has used hallucination detection models?
Krish NAik: Heard about it, but never used it.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Because in rag-based systems, you can do that even for LLM-based responses evaluation also, you can do that. That is one good thing.
Krish NAik: Okay, nobody has used it. Alright, fine, because I thought, only a few people might know about that. There are, certain models which can actually be integrated on top of your responses for things.
Krish NAik: You can get it in Hugging Face.
Krish NAik: I think HHMREF is there, okay? Three different variants of those type of models aren't there.
Krish NAik: Okay, I think, for that one…
Krish NAik: I don't know for, rack waste evaluation, if I show you.
Krish NAik: I have kept it somewhere that…
Krish NAik: Last year, I have tested, because now, in multimodal systems, actually, they keep it a lot.
Krish NAik: Where is the HCM rag?
Krish NAik: HHM rags, speech, text to seek email, okay? Yeah.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, like, I'm just telling you, HHM, as I'm telling it, like, this is one of the models that I really work with, even.
Krish NAik: Okay? Semantic highlighting also that can be used.
Krish NAik: Well, I'll be teaching.
Krish NAik: Patriot.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: This is the model that I was talking about.
Krish NAik: Very, few people are doing research on this one, and these guys are actually doing it, and I will say this is from Vectra.
Krish NAik: Their products are really good, okay, and this is an open source weight, which, if you want, you can actually utilize it.
Krish NAik: The next one is, semantic highlighting. Also, you have
Krish NAik: I think semantic, highlights from… if you want very specifically what type to do it, I'm just giving…
Krish NAik: Okay, so generally, for rack-based systems, from where actually you are getting… so, this is open-source thematic highlighter. So, similarly, multiple models are provided from multiple, I can say, providers. That way, you can always use these type of models to make your system much, much robust. And then those things, guardrails.
Krish NAik: Evaluation, RAGA, those things you can easily fit in, because there won't be any type of problems.
Krish NAik: For your backend testing, it means that these things should not be available to every client side. But from your backend side as a developer, you should do it, because a lot of initial testing, based on the incoming data through clients that you'll be getting. In that way, you can actually evaluate and provide and create a feedback system.
Krish NAik: Semantic highlighting means, from your chunks, exactly what is the core part that you need to look into.
Krish NAik: Okay, because in a chunk, you have a lot of information.
Krish NAik: Everything you don't need, no?
Krish NAik: So that's why that highlights exactly, from that chunk, what is the core important thing that is.
Krish NAik: How do you know about these models, Iva?
Krish NAik: Generally, in the RAG world, people, whoever is working with RAG-based systems, if you are actually doing
Krish NAik: Because I've spent a lot of time on rags last time.
Krish NAik: I think, for HHMRAG, Milverse was the one. I…
Krish NAik: they have, even for semantic highlighting, millbows. Major League Milvers, Vviate, and quadrant, they work, majorly on distance.
Krish NAik: So…
Krish NAik: Now, I think, I can close. Now, everybody please tell me that at least you guys have done it, because I feel that if you…
Krish NAik: have reached till this point. The next step is that we can move towards a little bit much more complex. The same thing can be hosted in a Kubernetes with much
Krish NAik: higher VRAM. Okay, scalability, not a problem, but at least if you have done this point, I will say that at least you are in a good state.
Krish NAik: Because really, like, very less people are working with open source. Everybody's all about consuming
Krish NAik: directly, I can say, LLMs, embedding models through APIs, rather than doing custom hosting of open widths, because this solution will be
Krish NAik: I can measure at least 75X cheaper.
Krish NAik: Always calculate it in long run, if you say for 1 hour.
Krish NAik: I cannot calculate it in one hour. In short term, this will be costly. Why? If you really think about one call to the anthropic model.
Krish NAik: Okay, let's stay, or to OpenAI. It is cheaper, if you really think about, because you need to pay for the GPU. The GPU cost, with respect to short-term, you will feel that it is high.
Krish NAik: Because you know that on-prem solution, it is a one-time cost.
Krish NAik: You have to pay it once, and majorly rest of the things, you really don't need to take care of any longer. But whereas, if you try to make continuous API calls, the solution cost will be high.
Krish NAik: Every financial solution, they are majorly working with Elastic.
Krish NAik: models.
Krish NAik: Okay, and Mistral model as their VLLM support. Mistral is the most open source and the famous family that I can say.
Krish NAik: Because that's how… their research is also pretty much old as compared.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me now kill the container, because, again, my credits are also getting exhausted. So, before switching off my machine, please let me know, like, anywhere.
Krish NAik: Satish is telling a multimodal Dopper Compose log warning.
Krish NAik: Value… Option, the model, removed in 0.3.
Krish NAik: Again, like, these are some separate warnings. It should run, right? It should run, but right now, the hyphen FN model option will be removed, VLLM server…
Krish NAik: Because I feel that you should not get… because, and this is also a warning, this is… know where there is an error till now.
Krish NAik: Latif.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Because this is…
Krish NAik: wait, wait for the service, wait, all you have… because it takes around 5 minutes, the VLLM container, to start up.
Krish NAik: Anybody else who is facing any issues?
Krish NAik: There's nothing about a bridge, because when you are actively in discussion every week, because that's why…
Krish NAik: The next batch, I'm planning about keeping a 30 minutes…
Krish NAik: session, just to inform everything what is happening here, Bing.
Krish NAik: In that way.
Krish NAik: Right, because I feel the lack of information. You have to spend a lot of time in the research part.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, guys, please tell me, can I, switch off my machine?
Krish NAik: Yes or no, should I keep it running?
Krish NAik: Satish, yes, I will look into your screen, don't worry. Because today, only this stack, only I have discussed the quain stack. Because going forward, I will be discussing the main deployment branch, I'll be doing the deployment in ECS Farget, ECS, those services, because the fourth project was a little bit…
Krish NAik: microservices architecture that we have used this side. We can break this into much more smaller microservices.
Krish NAik: But I felt that, like, you can keep a single instance for your re-ranker, one single instance for your embedding model everywhere, like, you can just hit those APIs. But I've kept it within the Python application. Later on, you can keep those things separate
Krish NAik: From that.
Krish NAik: I filled the, form last week, hope I, no, no, you don't need to fill it again, it's just for people who have missed it. Abhijit ya,
Krish NAik: I'm not dedicated to YouTube, that's why I don't, fail. Like, Treisha told me 4 years ago, but I'm not that type of guy, that every day I… I spend much more time in practical.
Krish NAik: Because, in YouTube, if you're actually giving a very detailed content, you don't get subscribed.
Krish NAik: You have to understand, niche content, nobody loves an email.
Krish NAik: Okay. That's why it's not worth it. In YouTube, we have to always make generic content.
Krish NAik: then only you get subscribers. So if I teach something in detail, I know that, the number of credits they give you.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I will switch up my machine right now, okay? So, I think…
Krish NAik: the number of credits, how much I have left. Close to… 17 or 15.
Krish NAik: Okay, 12 credits, 5 credits exhausted.
Krish NAik: But, remember from the next class, really, I don't need any GPU. I think, I need GPU for one thing, that is the Ulama.
Krish NAik: Because, my re-anchor model will be the same GINA API. So next, we will actually start with the deployment, okay, because I feel that, with respect to GitHub Actions, and then I will do the code discussion. Otherwise, during the discussion, there won't be any type of deployment fights.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why I think Saturday does, we'll be, completing that part. Okay, and now, one thing. Thursday, should I take a class or not?
Krish NAik: It can be any topic, but out of the syllabus, that's why.
Krish NAik: Because Saturday and Sunday, I'm not going to take those things, because my priority is right now to take that one, okay? Alright, fine.
Krish NAik: Then a little bit we'll be talking about page index. I think Krish also created the video page index, that is 19 minutes, but little bit with respect to, that, page index architecture, how they do it, okay, and where page index fails, that is the main important thing.
Krish NAik: Because page index works, but, really. In some cases, it fails also, that's all.
Krish NAik: Abhiji is telling, no, we need agent understanding. Agent understanding means, agent, Abhiji.
Krish NAik: That part, I could not, get it, okay? We need agent class. Agents will be normally, after next week, once we have done the deployment, both discussion will start with Langra. Saturday, Sunday, same thing, Abhiji, don't worry. Extra classes, that metadata enrichment.
Krish NAik: Then comes your… because for metadata enrichment, I told you, no, land extract way, and the other one was… when I forgot which way was there. One was the land…
Krish NAik: extract that I have pulled, and the other one was.
Krish NAik: No… Yeah, okay.
Krish NAik: Context of engineering.
Krish NAik: It's a little bit towards the theory, how to handle context window, those type of things, pretty much. It's not such a technical talk.
Krish NAik: like, prompt engineering, I can see.
Krish NAik: The new version of prompt engineering is context engineering, but again, I feel that
Krish NAik: In between that, there is a lot of gap parity.
Krish NAik: Okay, then the session, I'll be keeping it around, I think, 9.30. Okay, let's go for a 90-minute session. I think within 90 minutes, the pool discussion will be done. So, metadata enrichment, page vector index, any other thing that I'm forgetting, please let me know.
Krish NAik: From my site, with extra class. Meta data and other class, I attend on Wednesday. Not Wednesday, it will be Thursday. Wednesday, I have another batch.
Krish NAik: Architecture of VLLM, I'm not going to teach.
Krish NAik: Because for that, again, CNN fundamentals are a lot of things that comes into the picture.
Krish NAik: Mmm… Abhishek, Claude Coat, Claude Coat, I'm not,
Krish NAik: Again, like, everybody is not using cloud code, that is the main thing. Few people are working, and after last to last week, when the leak was there from the cloud code.
Krish NAik: I can say the spike of using codecs into the market spiked to 30-40%.
Krish NAik: Everybody switched to Codex after that particular week.
Krish NAik: Yes, it was a leak, though the Anthropic team told.
Krish NAik: That's why, again, the market certainly got down somehow.
Krish NAik: Which is better? It's totally an experience, Aniroth. Everybody has a different experience using this type of coding agent.
Krish NAik: Okay, somebody might love it, like, cloth is good, I love factory, okay, factory is also good, actually.
Krish NAik: So, it totally depends. Open code is also good. It totally depends upon your budget, how much you are willing to spend on these type of tools. Because I'm working with JLM 5.1, the new model that released, it's really, really good, up to the mark of
Krish NAik: Like, more than Sonnet 4.6 seconds.
Krish NAik: models are coming up, everyone is good, like, the speed is somewhere that matters. I feel the backend of OpenCode should be based on Rust or C++ at least, rather than completely keeping notes somehow. Yeah, it's faster, but I feel it's a little bit slow as compared to Cloud Code, Codex, and other regions.
Krish NAik: How is Windsoft daily? I paid to WinSoft for 6 months. Windsoft is good for an organization who can use it. They have their own models at, SW benchmark-based models. That does the job.
Krish NAik: similarly cursor. All are… I feel that's pretty much same family, with little bit up and downs.
Krish NAik: We are using actively, but credit finish. Yes, credit will finish, that's the nothing that I can do.
Krish NAik: That's why, when next time I'll be taking the advanced quarter, I'll be telling you, need at least, 200 credits or 300 credits.
Krish NAik: Because I have to do each practical, and I have to, for each practical, how much allocation time that you have to do
Krish NAik: The main problem is debugging. If somebody gets into the error.
Krish NAik: Okay, if you get into an error, to come out of that error from a GPU environment, you might need to spend a lot of time.
Krish NAik: Because you thought about, I will do the practical in 1 hour. You faced some type of problem. That becomes 4 hours. Automatically, the billing increases.
Krish NAik: That's the main thing, because you cannot actually test something on a CPU, though you might write the code that, okay, switch the platform from CPU to CUDA, okay, or MPS based on Apple machine, but, somewhere it fails. That's one.
Krish NAik: Yes, pretty much we are done today. I've switched off. Now, let me look into some of the questions, because I have my exams starting from, I think, 2 p.m. or 2.15pm today.
Krish NAik: But that's why a little bit, I have to look into
Krish NAik: the theoretical part of AI ethics and data governance.
Krish NAik: Those are laws, actually, European laws, those type of questions.
Krish NAik: Okay, guys, so tomorrow, no class, guys. Okay, so… and I think anything, everybody, I will suggest, at least do one. This one part.
Krish NAik: Because this experience, then you will really understand that working with a 40GB. Now, slowly, slowly, the requirements will be, like, try to make it much more compact. Pick up a 24GB machine, and see that, because that machine will be cheaper, and see that, okay, what are the models that I can fit in?
Krish NAik: go with the lightest, VLM model.
Krish NAik: Because when you are trying to build the cheapest solution in the market, on-prem, and the quality should be at least, because yes, when I move into the cheapest part, now the question comes.
Krish NAik: What is that trade-off?
Krish NAik: the trade-off can be from… because the model will be smaller, I can say the response time will be higher. But the quality of the response, and generally for rack-based systems.
Krish NAik: I have seen people, they are not using 1 billion models also. They are using simply, like, only million parameter model, 400 million parameters, they also work, because the entire thing depends upon what? Data parsing and chunky.
Krish NAik: That is the main thing. So really, like, you don't need good LLMs.
Krish NAik: We have been using a lot of GPT 4.0, but really, right now, we are in the field, when I simply say that, try to go something always less than… because I feel that 1 billion model is good, the new Gemma models, that you can test it out, but always be sure that if you're testing with multimodal support.
Krish NAik: They should have that support. That's the one. Pick up something lightest and multi, because this is what actually will be working.
Krish NAik: All right, so let's, start looking into, because for today, I am pretty much done. Are you doing doctorate? No, no, no, no, not doctorate, master's.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: B.
Krish NAik: Oh, the sh…
Krish NAik: Alright, Satish, you have raised your hand. Yeah, Satish, now tell me. Others, anybody who is facing some issues, otherwise you guys can drop. Next week, directly, we will start with the deployment of the, deployment branch. I think the GitHub Actions files are already configured.
Krish NAik: But, a few things I might change. Just be sure you are ready with your AWS accounts, create an IAM user. You should have your secrets ready, because these are the common paradigm that we have been following.
Krish NAik: Okay, now I am planning that, to keep it in two modes. One is the manual mode, and the other one is
Krish NAik: through CDK, okay, because the manual mode, or CDK or CDK, I can keep it in the last project. Okay, so whichever way that I decide, I will let you know in the next one.
Krish NAik: cloud formation I was planning, because to bring up the entire infra.
Krish NAik: So, let me see what we can do. So, Thursday, do we have the lecture? Yes, Thursday, we will be having the lecture from 9.30pm. I think, at least 9.30 PM, most of you will be coming back from offices.
Krish NAik: Yes? So, at least for Indian zones, I can separate Indian students.
Krish NAik: And this lecture will be small, anybody can look into the lecture later. That's why I'm not going to take long sessions.
Krish NAik: Ashoka Staling considers the using synthetic data, keeping portions on synthetic data, and…
Krish NAik: That is synthetic data generation, that is different, Nigel.
Krish NAik: Now, for RAG-based systems, you can simply do it using RAGAS. Okay. Now, for VLLM, it is different. Now, in VLLM, which format that matters. There are so many types of formats. The Alpaca format… okay, so based on, those formats, we do it.
Krish NAik: So, synthetic, that, previously in Dragar's part also I have shown.
Krish NAik: Using Ragas, you can do that. Now, do you suggest to go for… Totally, it, it's a personal choice, I mean.
Krish NAik: So, long-term in hire, after 10, 12 years, it might be some type of win.
Krish NAik: That's why I did it.
Krish NAik: everything will be in that, dashboard, Josephine. What those are, LLM knowledge bases under Skaphi?
Krish NAik: Alternative to RAG, there are so many alternatives now, the idea is who, cheap.
Krish NAik: Whether it is simple or not, if somehow you feel that if it is simple, you can adopt it. But if the complexity is much higher.
Krish NAik: It's just, like, a simple example of ReLU, because I know there are much better activation functions as compared to ReLU, but people have been using ReLU really a long time, just because of simplicity.
Krish NAik: Okay, LLM knowledge bases, slowly, slowly, the knowledge bases will increase as the computing power increases, but again, that option. Satish, so I'm adding you two panelists, start sharing your screen.
Krish NAik: Okay, Rahul, okay, you are a U.S. guys, so Ham, okay, everybody I'm unmuting, so one by one, you guys can go ahead and start.
Krish NAik: There are, two ones. Graphify has a close, concept to the vector analysis. But again, looking into the project, it looks good, but let's look into, actually, if people are using it.
Krish NAik: It in production, because really it takes up a little bit of time.
Krish NAik: I can say a lot of new things are coming, really. I feel that it's promising. Paige, like, again, like, when more and more test results come out based on benchmarks, then only we can take the final decision.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, I can say that here's good.
Krish NAik: All right.
Satish Tiwari: Can you see my screen visible?
Krish NAik: Yes, your screen is visible.
Satish Tiwari: When clicking this one, so not able to see that quadrant, okay, because it's running.
Krish NAik: Have you attended any classes till now?
Krish NAik: Of the multimodal record today directly, you came into the class.
Satish Tiwari: No, no, last weekend, I have attended.
Krish NAik: Then, how to access the web UI?
Krish NAik: Is this the way?
Satish Tiwari: T.
Krish NAik: Last to last class.
Satish Tiwari: I copied this one now.
Satish Tiwari: It's also not working.
Krish NAik: It doesn't work in that way, you have to do, both routing.
Satish Tiwari: You have to do both.
Krish NAik: routing. From the port bureau, you have to select the port, then you have to go there.
Krish NAik: And in your case, I can see that, right-hand side, that option is also not there. It means that you have never done the port routing.
Krish NAik: We have been doing port routing for many, many times. Now, look into that port, that USB option that you can see.
Krish NAik: USB option on the left-hand side, below the rocket sign.
Krish NAik: Below the rocket side on the… I think it's the right-hand side only, no, where you can see the VS window. You have not done a single time. Click on that.
Krish NAik: The USB one, the USB, USB plug, the USB below, below, below, below, below. Go for the last button that you guys see.
Satish Tiwari: profile.
Krish NAik: The last one. Above plus.
Satish Tiwari: Above Plaza.
Krish NAik: You have never done the port viewer option. For the past 2-3 weeks, we have been using it.
Krish NAik: Go and look into the lectures, don't skip the lectures.
Satish Tiwari: So here I have to give that 8000 points, correct?
Krish NAik: Here, you have to do the configuration, local, host, and which port that has been used for quadrant. Similarly, for FastAPI, you have to do all the configurations, and then you have to proceed right for the testing.
Krish NAik: Alright, I think, you can do these changes, and then you can… let me… yes. Sohal and Ram.
Soham Dutta: Yes, Paul, I have one question, Paul. I was trying… whatever you have created, no? I was trying to
Soham Dutta: create from the scratch, like, entire Docker, Compose, everything. Oh, right? So I… I don't have much of a DevOps experience, right? So let's see if I have to build something from scratch.
Soham Dutta: Docker Compose, how do I take a look? Where do I start with?
Soham Dutta: Like, I'm able to explain the flow, right? So, more than the technical, I was explained how… what was your thought process, and how have you developed the code, how have you connected different flows, how did… how have you got about thinking about the architecture, right? Now, I was… I'm focusing much more on that, so let's say if I have to create something like Docker Compose, right? Are there any resources that I should start with? Or probably, like, I just wanted to know how you are thinking
Soham Dutta: Beautiful.
Krish NAik: Let's say, see, generally, first of all, I always plan that, okay, in which container, what service will be run.
Soham Dutta: Okay, that is.
Krish NAik: the main thing. Once you have configured that, then you can look into the Docker Composer, a lot of examples in the official Docker website.
Soham Dutta: Right, right.
Krish NAik: From there, you can take a reference.
Krish NAik: And then exactly, once, before the Docker, once you are testing the application locally, then what are the ports that you are, like, once you have figured that this is the port for Quadrant, this is the port for Volama, then comes basically making the connections, the interconnections among the containers.
Krish NAik: Now, this is how. I simply, first of all, decide that, okay, how many containers I need. Now, what will be the services that will be running within that container, and finally, what are the codes. Once I have these information, I'm good to go.
Soham Dutta: Okay, got it.
Krish NAik: And there can be certain things for which, rather than the application directly, you can get a Docker image. Okay, in that case, rather than going the scratch way, writing up the application, I download the Docker image from DockerHub when the container starts, and I run that within the container directly.
Krish NAik: that, whichever container image, like in this case, I have taken VLLM. Rather than installing it manually, I have taken the Dopper image out.
Soham Dutta: Right, right, right, got it.
Soham Dutta: Thank you.
Krish NAik: So, always decide that, that, because if I want to break it into much more microservices, I can, like, one container for re-ranker, one container for your embedding, so everything will be hitting those containers.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in that way, you can break it much more, just for safety, because here, what happens if one service is down in the poor application, okay, and by default, I can say that the rest of the things becomes a problem, because it's pretty much interconnected.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, you have to keep as a… always a, like, a failsafe condition. Like, if this doesn't work, then switch back to an API or something like that.
Soham Dutta: Last question on this is, like, when you have, after the class, whenever, right, half an hour, can you just walk us through, like, how different service containers you actually keep, right? Like, let's see if you have to create something from scratch, can you just give us pseudo-architecture, like, how do you think about it?
Krish NAik: Any agent take rag part, I will keep it, because there are other containers for every service. Think about any service that you would think, because a separate container for Grafana, a separate container for Prometheus, other services that you actually use it in production.
Krish NAik: container for airflow. In that way, we try to break it, at least. Like, 8 to 10 containers are pretty much common, it can be more than that.
Krish NAik: Okay, in the next project, I will be giving you data rough item.
Soham Dutta: Okay, okay, okay, thank you.
Rahul Parihar: So, Paul, my question is real,
Rahul Parihar: Really related to productionizing some of the…
Rahul Parihar: proof of concept, like multimodel one, okay? This is solving one of the brain problems, but what I'm trying to do is, if I say if I'm creating a deal intelligence agent, you know, or… which has 100 set of, you know, deals, and right now.
Rahul Parihar: If the team takes about 20 days to sort a deal, and now it's with the agentic solution, system.
Rahul Parihar: So, wanted to combine the brain of generative AI and solve it with an agentic AI problem, that you take a task, take a goal.
Rahul Parihar: And try to, iterate it unless and until this is not done.
Rahul Parihar: So, making it more adoptive, kind of, for RAG, where, you know, there is a judge, if the content doesn't come in through, you know, you would iterate it, generate it, till I don't get my…
Rahul Parihar: my answer, you know, on a specific task, on a specific goal, and until that goal is not met.
Rahul Parihar: Could you do…
Rahul Parihar: in one of the… you asked, like, one of the sessions, like, how to marry generative AI with agentic AI,
Rahul Parihar: and marry that together, you know, some…
Krish NAik: I've got it in the sea, but again, like, in the next project, I have not kept it multimodal. I've kept it simple only, because again, G2, I don't want to bring into the picture, but in the next agentic project that I have, there are much more other services that I have included. I'm planning also to bring Celery and other things.
Krish NAik: But, in the next project, it will be much more clear, because the thing that you are telling, you will get the idea from there, because I have done the orchestration through Langraph.
Krish NAik: And within, like, multiple RAG agents that will be running, I think 2 or 3 RAG agents, but those RAG agents are text, okay? It's not multimodal support at the end.
Krish NAik: That part, later on, you can upgrade it. So in the next project, that part will be much more clear.
Krish NAik: And…
Rahul Parihar: what if we want to host this kind of a model, right? Like, on a local GPU system initially? So what would be the costing of that particular GPU model would look like, you know, if we are trying to host it?
Rahul Parihar: Like, initially…
Krish NAik: a one-time cost of the hardware, the GPU, and then comes your main, like, generally for these, we purchase, those.
Krish NAik: Europe,
Krish NAik: bare metal servers, which set up the entire infra, whether through OpenCloud is there. So many, like, multiple providers out there. You can take up a bare machine with a GPU, bare metal with the local GPU support. Now, the question comes on-prem when I'm telling.
Krish NAik: like, on an Intel Xeon server, backend, with a… You can, because the cost of the GPU will be high, because that is around… in India, I know that 12 lakh, that comes around.
Krish NAik: For, H200s, if you are going ahead with P200s… Okay, the cost will increase, because the cost of the GPU is pretty much high as compared to the server's cost will be…
Krish NAik: one-third of that, or even, I can say, one-fourth of that. The major portion goes to the GP. But, if you are using a GP, just think about, from future perspective, like, how much it will scale up.
Krish NAik: like, if you are trying to scale up, then you have to understand that I need another GP. For example, if you are getting 1 lakh request.
Krish NAik: every second, then you need 2 to 3 GB.
Krish NAik: Because then, the same Docker container, you have to, basically run multiple containers in one shot. Based on the number of requests, again, you will,
Krish NAik: basically open more containers, so the requests are redirected through a load balancer to them. So those type of setup, because the bare metal setup, it is a one-time setup.
Krish NAik: It might take you 2 to 3 weeks to do the setup, but worth it for majorly all the financial institutions are working on those type of solutions only.
Rahul Parihar: Can you give some flavor, like, can you drop some documentation of bare metal,
Krish NAik: Paint.
Rahul Parihar: and Z.
Krish NAik: it was.
Krish NAik: Bare metal pricing, you can get it in internet, see, now comes, are you getting the server online? Or, you want it on-prem? That is the decision.
Rahul Parihar: online.
Krish NAik: one.
Krish NAik: Online. Online is cheaper.
Krish NAik: I think, yearly-based subscriptions of bare-metal servers… bare metal, a lot of providers are there, just wait.
Krish NAik: the same thing?
Rahul Parihar: Enterprise-grade, servers, right? Like, they are enterprise-grade servers, they are not, like, security-prone and SOC-compliant servers, right?
Krish NAik: No, no, no, no, like, they are majorly, like, you can see Hostinger provides, hostinger, I know I've used it. OVH Cloud, this is also good. Open Metal, this is… a lot of providers are there in the market. From wherever you are getting the cheapest one, you can pick up that.
Krish NAik: Because the bare metal setup, really takes 2-3 weeks, we have to sit a little bit with the DevOps guys.
Krish NAik: Because a few things with respect to OpenCloud and others, like, or doing the entire Kubernetes installation from scratch, in those cases, I feel having that, DevOps expertise is
Krish NAik: better, if I am not doing… Contabo is also… I've used Contabo, it's one of the cheapest. So, there are so many providers. In the US, I think there is one provider, I forgot that name. They are actually the best
Krish NAik: And very, very old organization. In Chicago, they have dedicated servers in 3 to 4 regions. Vultures is also good, but, okay, pricing part, if I go into…
Krish NAik: Generally, if I go ahead with a 32V CPUs, 120GB. Now, this is roughly coming around $1 per hour.
Krish NAik: Okay, and the storage is blocked storage, just, I think blocked… you should get an NVMe SSD.
Krish NAik: Okay, so SSDs will be a little bit costlier.
Krish NAik: But, I think, 240GB or 440GB with 16V CPU is good. Like, Vulture is a really good one in the old organization. They have, cloud GPUs also.
Krish NAik: directly you can bring it. Vulture, you can look into, because if you contact the Vulture team, they will give you, I think, $200 credits also, to do your initial bare-metal testing. So that is enough, at least, to set up your own info.
Krish NAik: If you want to get it for your initiative. Once you have this, then the same thing, you can get it from AWS, GCP, everybody has.
Krish NAik: Because at the end of the day, if you think about it, it's pretty much an instance.
Krish NAik: But that setup, documentation… about, I think, that Indian startup was there, what is that?
Krish NAik: I think the name is Dukan, no?
Krish NAik: That was a great, video just with, took on.
Krish NAik: YouTube video, bare metal, they actually moved the entire info.
Krish NAik: Mom.
Krish NAik: Let me just flip it.
Krish NAik: Because they have a lot of clients, and they have actually made the switch from cloud to this one.
Krish NAik: Yes, this video. Just have a look into this. This will give you a good idea with respect to applications, actually.
Rahul Parihar: Okay.
Krish NAik: Okay, now.
Krish NAik: Because, see, this is a use case that they have told, actually, a lot of, other, things with respect to what is the stack that they have used.
Krish NAik: Now, switching up one server, like, they have multiple pyramidal servers, like, in India Zone 1, in the US. Now, if you are actually switching up one of the servers in India, then how to make a switch to the US server? A lot of, good use case was there. Actually, I…
Krish NAik: watched this video, and then I did a setup. I think, back in 2025 or 2024,
Krish NAik: around that time. But this is a good video because they have a lot of clients, and I'm sharing this video if anybody's interested in parametal servers. This is a really good, and from cost perspective, how it impacted, so really a good use case. You can actually have a look into this.
Rahul Parihar: Okay.
Krish NAik: It's one hour long, but stick to it, because the insights are really good.
Krish NAik: From production point of view, he actually shows, in production, the server is sitting just beside him. Okay, he has the server, he switches off the Indian server, and he actually shows that. In real time. So…
Rahul Parihar: But if the multi-model have to be run on a CPU, what CPU configuration should be selected? Like, you're talking about GPU versus CPU comparison, right?
Krish NAik: If you want a GPU, then very specifically.
Rahul Parihar: No, no, the multimodel, if I'm running it, like, very low, concurrency, about 10 to 20 people, only skilled people are trying to do the deals, but trying to find out from hundreds of deals, or thousands of deals, you know, data mapping and parsing the data.
Rahul Parihar: For… if the concurrency load, then it will run… it can run on GPU, right? Or CPU, right?
Krish NAik: Obviously, you have to plan in that way, because you have the requirement of GPU, where you want to use it, very specifically. Whether you want to use it in the data ingestion pipeline, I feel that that is one of the major bottlenecks. It means that the data ingestion pipeline can take more time.
Krish NAik: Whereas, whenever you are working with respect to any query-based, like the retrieval-based system, it will be much faster. In that case.
Krish NAik: I don't feel you always need the GP. You can skip it.
Krish NAik: But at least for data ingestion, there is no other option, because layout detection, OCR-based models, or you're working with a single unistage model, like Nemotron Pass.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, you can switch to APIs, but again, like, Nestral API and others.
Krish NAik: that cost will come. But if you're thinking about to host everything, like a Quen family that we have done it. In that case, there is no option. It means that you need a GPU, but just be sure the amount of GPU that you are using, it should be at least pushed to
Krish NAik: Like, 100GB of VRAM, it should.
Krish NAik: If you think in sums, it might at least reach 5,000 requests per second.
Krish NAik: If you feel that only 10 to 20 requests, or 50 requests, or even 500 requests, you can use around, like, 80GB of instance for the safer site. But don't use 40GB instances, nobody uses it in production.
Krish NAik: Because once you have done the entire application, see how much room you have.
Krish NAik: The room should be at least 30% of your total GPU.
Krish NAik: Do that simple calculation, and based on that, you can decide.
Rahul Parihar: Cut it. Okay.
Rahul Parihar: Makes sense. Thanks, Folly.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Anybody else? You can let me know.
Krish NAik: Satesh, have you done any, those considerations?
Satish Tiwari: Yes, I have… I have added that quote, okay, it's working, and we'll check, okay.
Satish Tiwari: Oh, thank you.
Krish NAik: Now, see, if the quadrant is up and running, if VLLM is up and running, so step by step, the things that I have put. Check each thing's… okay, check, and at least, the GLM OCR is using the GP. If it is using the CPU, again, like, you will face some problems that I can see.
Krish NAik: Okay? Alright guys, everybody please do the practical, ones.
Krish NAik: Hmm…
Satish Tiwari: So tomorrow, you know Class, correct?
Krish NAik: Yeah, guys, tomorrow there is no class, like, tomorrow.
Krish NAik: Like, every student in my, cohort told that they are free on Saturday, Sunday, nothing I can do. I only was the guy who voted on Monday and Tuesday.
Krish NAik: That's why I was in the minority.
Krish NAik: Alright, is the session completed? Yes, Sam. So everybody, whoever, like, let's see, the other way around, that I felt that I've,
Krish NAik: From a single IP, you cannot create multiple accounts. But whenever you are changing the region or a different place.
Krish NAik: then try to create the account, because if you use VPNs also, then also it doesn't.
Krish NAik: I have tested, that's what I'm telling. I have 3 to 4 accounts, but I've created, like, when I was in Delhi, I created one when I go, I created one in that way. I do have multiple emails for my particular domain, send that way. Okay, so if you feel that, try to create an account, then use that. Change the location, and then only.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I think then we are good for today. So guys, you can drop everyone. Okay, so next session, we will start with the AWS deployment, just be sure, because I don't want to spend time on creating IAM users.
Krish NAik: I'm just… I will talk about, what are the permissions which are required. So, quickly, I will share that, and you guys can select. So, just be sure. Your terminal is configured. When you do an AWS,
Krish NAik: STS Identity Caller, okay, you should see that that IAM user is activated. So, just be sure in next Saturday class, you have that
Krish NAik: And the same thing, I will remind you on Thursday also. On Thursday, you'll be having the class from 9.30 to 11. Okay, let's go for 90-minute session, and something, like, whether it's page index or metadata enrichment, something I'll be discussing.
Krish NAik: No class tomorrow, yes, correct Abhishek.
Krish NAik: Okay, I think we are good. Any other questions?
Krish NAik: I think, no more questions. Correct. Fine, everyone. So, bye-bye. Thanks for joining.